planted.com 2019-02-03

# Planted: Grow Your Career at a Job You’ll Love

Effective date: May 24, 2018 

We at Planted know you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. 

**By using or accessing Planted’s website or the Services in any manner, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy, and you hereby consent that we will collect, use, and share your information in the following ways.**

Remember that your use of Planted’s Services is at all times subject to the Terms of Service, which incorporates this Privacy Policy. Any terms we use in this Policy without defining them have the definitions given to them in the Terms of Service. 

###  What does this Privacy Policy cover?

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) that we gather when you are accessing or using our Services, but not to the practices of companies we do not own or control, or people that we do not manage. We gather various types of Personal Information from our users, as explained in more detail below, and we use this Personal Information internally in connection with our Services, including to personalize, provide, and improve our services, to allow you to set up a user account and profile, to contact you and allow other users to contact you, to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, and to analyze how you use the Services. In certain cases, we may also share some Personal Information with third parties, but only as described below. 

As noted in the Terms of Service, we do not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for the Services or send any Personal Information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected Personal Information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 13 may have provided us Personal Information, please contact us at [support@planted.com](mailto:support@planted.com).

Planted will only retain your Personal Information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes it collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. To determine the appropriate retention period for Personal Information, Planted considers the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the Personal Information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your Personal Information, the purposes for which Planted processes your Personal Information and whether it can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. 

Planted does not process your Personal Information using automated decision-making. 

### Will Planted ever change this Privacy Policy?

We are constantly trying to improve our Services, so we may need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time as well, but we will alert you to changes by placing a notice on the www.planted.com website, by sending you an email, and/or by some other means. Please note that if you have opted not to receive legal notice emails from us (or you have not provided us with your email address), those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are still responsible for reading and understanding them. If you use the Services after any changes to the Privacy Policy have been posted, that means you agree to all of the changes. 

This version of the Privacy Policy was last updated on May 24, 2018 and historic versions can be obtained by contacting Planted. 

### What Information does Planted Collect?

_Information You Provide to Us_

We receive and store any information you knowingly provide to us. For example, through the registration process and/or through your account settings, we may collect Personal Information such as your name, email address, phone number, and resume information. Certain information may be required to register with us or to take advantage of some of our features. 

We may communicate with you if you have provided us the means to do so. For example, if you have given us your email address, we may send you promotional email offers on behalf of other businesses, or email you about your use of the Services. Also, we may receive a confirmation when you open an email from us. This confirmation helps us make our communications with you more interesting and improve our services. If you do not want to receive communications from us, please indicate your preference by contacting support@planted.com.

_Information Collected Automatically_

Whenever you interact with our Services, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser or device, which may include your IP address, location information, device identification, “cookie” information, the type of browser and/or device you are using to access our Services, and the page or feature you requested. “Cookies” are identifiers we transfer to your browser or device that allow us to recognize your browser or device and tell us how and when pages and features in our Services are visited and by how many people. You may be able to change the preferences on your browser or device to prevent or limit your device’s acceptance of cookies, but this may prevent you from taking advantage of some of our features. Planted also collects technical data from various third parties and public sources, such as analytics providers, advertising networks and search information providers. If you click on a link to a third party website or service, such third party may also transmit cookies to you. Again, this Privacy Policy does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties, and we are not responsible for their privacy policies and practices. Please see our Cookie Policy for more information about the cookies that we use. 

We may use this data to customize content for you that we think you might like, based on your usage patterns. We may also use it to improve the Services – for example, this data can tell us how often users use a particular feature of the Services, and we can use that knowledge to make the Services interesting to as many users as possible. 

Other than as required by law, we do not collect any special categories of personal information about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). 

Planted will only use your Personal Information for the purposes for which it was collected, unless it reasonably considers that it needs to use it for another reason that is compatible with the original purpose. If Planted needs to use your Personal Information for an unrelated purpose, Planted will notify you and explain the legal basis which allows Planted to do so. 

_Information Collected From Other Websites and Do Not Track Policy_

Through cookies we place on your browser or device, we may collect information about your online activity after you leave our Services. Just like any other usage information we collect, this information allows us to improve the Services and customize your online experience, and otherwise as described in this Privacy Policy. Your browser may offer you a “Do Not Track” option, which allows you to signal to operators of websites and web applications and services (including behavioral advertising services) that you do not wish such operators to track certain of your online activities over time and/or across different websites. Our Services do not support Do Not Track requests at this time, which means that we collect information about your online activity both while you are using the Services and after you leave our Services. 

###  Will Planted Share Any of the Personal Information it Receives? 

We neither rent nor sell your Personal Information in personally identifiable form to anyone. However, we may share your Personal Information with third parties as described in this section: 

**Information that is no longer personally identifiable:** We may anonymize your Personal Information so that you are not individually identified, and provide that information to our partners. We may also provide aggregate usage information to our partners, who may use such information to understand how often and in what ways people use our Services, so that they, too, can provide you with an optimal online experience. However, we never disclose aggregate information to a partner in a manner that would identify you personally, as an individual. 

**Affiliated Businesses:** In certain situations, businesses or third party websites we are affiliated with may sell or provide products or services to you through or in connection with the Services (either alone or jointly with us). You can recognize when an affiliated business is associated with such a transaction or service, and we will share your Personal Information with that affiliated business only to the extent that it is related to such transaction or service. One such service may include the ability for you to search employers seeking candidates and automatically send such prospective employers a copy of your resume. We have no control over the policies and practices of third party websites or businesses as to privacy or anything else, so if you choose to take part in any transaction or service relating to an affiliated website or business, please review all such business’ or websites’ policies. 

**Agents and Advisors:** We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you; for example, we may use a customer service company to help us troubleshoot technical difficulties you may encounter or to assist with marketing campaigns. Unless we tell you differently, our agents do not have any right to use the Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. 

**User Profiles and Submissions:** Certain user profile information, including your name, location, and any video or image content that such user has uploaded to the Services, may be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within the Services or address your request for our services. Please remember that any content you upload to your public user profile, along with any Personal Information or content that you voluntarily disclose online in a manner other users can view (on discussion boards, in messages, etc.) becomes publicly available, and can be collected and used by anyone. Your user name may also be displayed to other users if and when you send messages or comments through the Services and other users can contact you through the Services. 

**Business Transfers:** We may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that would be transferred. Also, if we (or our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, Personal Information could be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party. 

**Protection of Planted and Others:** We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information that we believe is necessary to comply with law or court order; enforce or apply our Terms of Service and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Planted, our employees, our users, or others. 

If your Personal Information is protected by EU data protection law, Planted’s legal basis for collecting and using the Personal Information described above will depend on the Personal Information concerned and the specific context in which Planted collects it. 

However, Planted will normally collect Personal Information from you only (a) where it needs the personal information to perform a contract with you, (b) where the processing is in its legitimate interests and is not overridden by your rights, or (c) where it has your consent to do so. If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which Planted collects and uses your Personal Information, please contact Planted using the contact details provided below. 

###  Is Personal Information about me secure? 

Planted protects your Personal Information in the same way that it protects its other confidential information, such as storing it on secure servers that only select Planted personnel have access to, and by encrypting it to help prevent access by any unauthorized parties. Planted has put in place procedures to deal with any Personal Information breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach when legally required to do so. Your account is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You must prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer or device and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. 

We endeavor to protect the privacy of your account and other Personal Information we hold in our records, but unfortunately, we cannot guarantee complete security. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time. 

###  What Personal Information can I access? 

Through your account settings, you may access, and, in some cases, edit or delete the following information you’ve provided to us, such as: 

  * name and password 
  * email address 
  * location 
  * resume 
  * education 
  * profile photo 

The information you can view, update, and delete may change as the Services change. If you have any questions about viewing or updating information we have on file about you, please contact us at [support@planted.com.](mailto:support@planted.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy)

Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of Personal Information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to: Planted, Inc., 240 Kent Avenue, Brooklyn, NY 11249. 

###  EU Data Protection Rights 

If your Personal Information is protected by EU data protection law, you have the following data protection rights which you may be able to exercise by contacting Planted using the contact details provided below: 

  * If you wish to access, correct, update or request deletion of your Personal Information, you can do so at any time by contacting Planted. 
  * In addition, you can object to processing of your Personal Information, ask Planted to restrict processing of your Personal Information or request portability of your Personal Information by contacting Planted. 
  * You have the right to opt-out of marketing communications that Planted sends you at any time. You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the marketing emails Planted sends you or by using the relevant opt-out mechanism for non-email based marketing. 
  * Similarly, if Planted has collected and processes your Personal Information based on your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing Planted conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your Personal Information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent. 
  * You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about Planted’s collection and use of your Personal Information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. 

You will not have to pay a fee to access your Personal Information (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, Planted may charge a reasonable fee or refuse to comply with your request if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Planted tries to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally, it may take longer if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, Planted will notify you and keep you updated. 

###  International Transfers 

Planted processes information on servers in many countries around the world and you consent to your Personal Information being processed on a server located outside the country in which you reside. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country (and, in some cases, may not be as protective). However, Planted has taken appropriate safeguards to require that your Personal Information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy, including, when applicable utilizing the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of Personal Information between its group companies, which requires all group companies to protect Personal Information being processed from the European Economic Area to an equivalent standard to that required under European Union data protection law. 

###  What choices do I have? 

You can always opt not to disclose information to us, but keep in mind some information may be needed to register with us or to take advantage of some of our features. 

You may be able to add, update, or delete information as explained above. When you update information, however, we may maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. You may request deletion of your account by contacting [support@planted.com](mailto:support@planted.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy). Some information may remain in our records after your deletion of such information from your account. We may use any aggregated data derived from or incorporating your Personal Information after you update or delete it, but not in a manner that would identify you personally. 

###  What if I have questions about this policy? 

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policy, please send us a detailed message to [support@planted.com](mailto:support@planted.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy) or write to us at Planted, Inc., 240 Kent Avenue, Brooklyn NY 11249, and we will try to resolve your concerns.
